

Summary

After gaining a beginner's foundations in computer science at college and in web development at Dev Bootcamp, I am excited to build on those foundations by contributing to a web development team.

> Skills

LANGUAGES: Ruby, Javascript, HTML/CSS, PHP (some), SQL (some)

WEB FRAMEWORKS: Rails, Laravel, React.js, Sinatra

METHODOLOGIES: Test-driven development, Object oriented design, Version control

ADOBE CS (SOME EXPERIENCE): Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign

> Education

Dev Bootcamp Chicago

Web Development 2014

Completed a 19-week, intensive program teaching Ruby, Rails, Javascript, SQL, HTML, CSS, TDD, Git, and pair-programming.

Hendrix College

B.A. English 2014

3.88 GPA

Relevant courses: Data Structures (Java), Computing Systems Organization (C, assembly), Foundations of CS (Python), Discrete Math, Calculus

> Projects

Posy

- · Anonymously post and comment on complimentary messages for local communities (colleges, etc.).
- Single page for reading, posting, commenting, and flagging content.
- React.js, Rails, RSpec

Judgy

- Users upload a photo, answer questions, and then make and receive guesses about answers based only on the photo.
- Laravel (PHP), Javascript, AWS S3, PHPUnit, Gulp, Bootstrap

ExitSlips

- Create, grade, and map short quizzes to Common Core standards. Data is automatically compiled and easily displayed and exported as CSV.
- · Built in seven days with team of four at Dev Bootcamp Chicago
- · Rails, Javascript

> Employment

The Profile (Hendrix College newspaper)

Aug 2011 to May 2012, Aug 2013 to May 2014

Photo Editor

Managed a staff of 3-5 photographers and designed/coordinated photo coverage for a student-run newspaper.

Conway, AR

Little Rock, AR

Arkansas Business Publishing Group

Photography Intern (paid)

May 2014 to Aug 2014

Fulfilled assignments from a variety of publications including Arkansas Business, Little Rock Soiree, Arkansas Next, Capital Assets, and Metro.

Saline Courier May 2014 to Aug 2014

Staff photographer Benton, AR

Responsible for the majority of photo coverage for a daily newspaper, either through assignments or freelancing. Won multiple awards in statewide competitions.